呃喔  爹地来了
Uh-oh! Dad's here.
甜甜圈们  快逃命吧
Donuts! Run for your lives!
击个掌
Up top.
已经不搞笑了  老爸体重减了不少了
It's not funny anymore. Dad's lost a bunch of weight.
感激涕零啊  老爹  你减肥毁了我最经典的笑话
Thanks a lot, dad. You got skinny and killed all my best material.
说到这了  我瘦了不少了
Actually, I've lost so much weight,
我现在可以在普通服装店里买衣服了
I gotta start buying my clothes in a regular store now.
不再去“班尼肥大特制服装店”了
No more "Benny's Huge and Bald"?
兰尼高大强壮服装店
"Lenny's Big and Tall".
但我喜欢兰尼店
But I love Lenny's.
那是家独一无二的店  有钢结构支撑的试衣间
It's the only store with steel-reinforced dressing rooms.
那是家独一无二的店  把货物入口当正门
The only store where the freight entrance is also the main entrance.
哦  稍等  好  我想到一个笑话
Okay, wait wait. Okay, I got one.
那是家独一无二的店  大号衣服很大而小号的
It's the only store where the large sizes are big and the small ones...
不会
Aren't.
好吧  我猜这不是个笑话
Yeah, I guess I don't got one.
那好  我去商场了
All right. I'm off to the Mall.
哇  光明正大的逛街
Wow. Shopping without shame.
真是全新的体验
This is gonna be different.
嘿  老爸  你可别买假发
Hey, dad. Just don't get a hairpiece.
我是说  你总得给我留点可嘲笑的东西
I mean, you gotta leave me something.
那是一个大人很胖
Where the big people are so fat...
-PJ  我们玩完了  -好的
- P.J., we're done. - Okay.
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
生活搞得一团糟
<i>Today's all burnt toast </i>
就要迟到  爸爸在叫
<i>Running late, and dad jokes</i>
我左脚的鞋子有没有人看到
<i>Has anybody seen my left shoe</i>
我闭上眼  咬口早餐
<i>I close my eyes, take a bite</i>
■
翻译： 不远景  Tracy
跳上车子  放声大笑
<i>Grab a ride, laugh out loud</i>
哎呀  老爸  鞋子就在房顶上
<i>There it is up on the roof.</i>
我也曾这样生活  我已经顺利走过
<i>I've been there, I survived.</i>
■
校订： Enpistu
所以听取我的建议
<i>So just take my advice.</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby</i>
■
后期： Enpistu  liloelva
世界有很多疯狂无奈
<i>Things are crazy</i>
可是我知道你会有美好将来
<i>But I know your future's bright.</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby</i>
不要怀疑
<i>There's no maybe</i>
一切终会如你所愿
<i>Everything turns out all right.</i>
生活有悲有喜
<i>Sure life is up and down.</i>
但是请相信我  坚持就有好结果
<i>But trust me, it comes back around.</i>
你会喜欢将来的你
<i>You're gonna love who you turn out to be.</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby.</i>
查莉成长日记  第三季第十八集
Good Luck Charlie  S03E18  The Charlie Whisperer
天大好消息  还记得我写的那个剧本吗
Great news! Remember that play I wrote?
-舞动的小公主  -是的
- "The dancing Princess"?  - Yeah.
我们剧目组要公开演出  由艾薇担任导演
My theater group is doing the production and Ivy's directing.
要我来主演吗
And I'm starring?
-不是  -噢
- No.  - Oh.
那好消息是什么
Then what's the great news?
那个  母亲大人您不是主演  但您猜谁是
Well, you're not in this one, mom, but guess who is.
查莉哦
Charlie!
我要成为公主啦
I'm gonna be a Princess.
恭喜啊
Good for you.
希望演艺事业不会令你心碎  就像我
Hope show business doesn't break your heart as it did mine.
嗨  查莉  那个熊怎么还在地上
Hey, Charlie. Why is that bear still on the floor?
我一个小时前就让你捡起来了
I asked you to pick that up an hour ago.
嘿  公主  我不想再说一遍了
Hey, Princess. I'm not gonna ask you again.
赶快把熊捡起来
Pick up the bear now.
不要
No.
她一整天都这样
She's been like this all day.
老妈  让我来
Mom. If I may...
查莉  小甜心
Charlie, sweetie.
帮大姐姐个忙把熊捡起来好不好啊
Could you pick up that bear for your big sister, please?
好啊
Okay.
您还需要让她做什么  找我就好
If you need her to do anything else, just let me know.
她才三岁  你这是碰巧
She's three years old. You got lucky.
不  才不是运气呢
No no. It's not luck.
小查莉和我有一种特殊的姐妹情
Charlie and I have a special sister bond.
您可以说我是  小查莉密语者
I guess you could call me "The Charlie Whisperer".
小查莉密语者
"The Charlie Whisperer".
好啊  你要真那么厉害  为什么不让她从你屋里出来
Okay. Well, if you're so good, why don't you get her to come out of your room?
我用意念就做到了
I did that one with my mind.
你在做什么
What you working on?
哦  英语作业
Oh, it's for English.
我需要写一篇关于一个老人的报告
I have to write a report about an old person.
我的邻居伯特  作者盖比·邓肯
"My neighbor Bert... By Gabe Duncan".
伯特·窦艮  一个丈夫  父亲
"Bert Doogan... Husband, Father...
宇航员
Astronaut"?
哇哦
Whoa!
我还真没听说过怪脾气的老伯特曾经是宇航员啊
I didn't know grumpy old Bert was an Astronaut.
怪脾气的老伯特自己也没听说过
Neither does grumpy old Bert.
我瞎编的
I made the whole thing up.
要不然我就得真的和那老家伙谈话了
It was either that or actually talking to the old dude.
当我帮伯特先生修剪草坪时
"Whenever I mow Bert's lawn,
他总是讲起他那神奇的宇宙探险历程
he tells me stories about his adventures in space".
曾经有一回他的火箭漏了个洞  于是他用牙膏
"There was this one time where his rocket sprung a leak and he fixed it,
和月球上的岩石修好了它
with toothpaste and moon rocks".
拜托  老弟  没人会信的
Come on, dude! No one's gonna believe that.
怎么  月球岩石太假了
What, the moon rocks?
不是  假的是你帮别人修剪草坪
No, that you mowed somebody's lawn.
噢
Oh!
哦  这岂不是我最爱的编剧吗
Oh, there's my favorite playwright.
这不是我最爱的导演吗
There's my favorite Director!
这实在太令人激动了  我都不知道你会想当导演
This is so exciting. I didn't even know you wanted to direct.
你开玩笑吗  我说话很大声  我喜欢使唤人
Are you kidding? I talk loud, I like to boss people around...
我天生就是这块料
I'm a natural.
我们来讨论一下演员吧
Now let's talk casting.
好啊
Yes!
好的
Okay.
那好  嗯  至少我们可以确定谁来出演小公主
Well, uh, at least we know who's gonna play the young Princess...
-查莉  -哇哦
- Charlie. - Whoa.
别太着急
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
查莉也得和其他人一样参加试镜
Charlie's got to audition like everybody else.
好吧  我明白了
Okay, I get it.
你是想让查莉参加一次
You want me to bring Charlie in for an...
试镜
"Audition".
是的  我
Yes, I...
确有此意
"Do".
艾薇  你看哈  总共就只有一句台词
Ivy, look. It's just one line and
我是专门为查莉写的
I wrote it for Charlie.
如果她能念出来  她就可以参演哦
And if she can say it, she gets the part.
您好
Hello.
邓肯夫人  请不要再给我打电话了  您不能参演
Mrs. Duncan, please stop calling me. You cannot be in the play.
大家好啊
Hey, guys.
那是什么
What was that?
嗯  亲爱的  鲍伯
Uh... Bob, honey?
能出来一下吗
Could you come out here please?
你穿的那是什么
Whatcha wearing?
什么啊  这个么
What, this?
在商场买的
Got it at the Mall.
不管怎样  反正是家普通的服装店
Yeah, some regular store. Whatever.
哦  那家店叫“衣山”  山峰的山
Oh, the place was called "Cloz", with a "Z".
衣山
Cloz?
我也在那买衣服
I shop there.
至少以前在那买
At least I used to.
呃  我对这家“衣山”有个疑问
Ooh, question about this "Cloz" with a "Z"...
他们家有镜子和灯吗
Um, do they have mirrors or lights?
好了好了好了  我知道你们在想什么
All right, all right. All right, fine. I know what you're thinking.
嗨  最开始我也不知道新形象好不好  不过你猜怎样
Hey, at first, I wasn't sure about this new look either. But you know what?
大家都在夸我
Everybody kept complimenting me.
开玩笑吧
Really?
他们说我“穿着有范”
Yeah, they said I was "making it work".
“力挺这一身”
"Rockin' that outfit".
还有  “仔裤杀手”
Oh, yeah... "Killin' those jeans".
我不确定最后一条是不是赞美
Not sure that last one was a compliment.
综上就是我的邻居伯特振奋人心的故事
And those are the kind of uplifting stories
这是他在我哥PJ帮忙修剪草坪时
my neighbor Bert tells me whenever my brother P.J.
讲给我听的
Mows his lawn.
盖比  刚刚太精彩了  谢谢
Gabe, that was wonderful. Thank you.
哪有  感谢您为我布置了这次作业
No, thank you for giving me the assignment.
既然伯特是一位如此不可思议的人物
You know, Bert sounds like an incredible man.
你能请他到班上来给大家讲两句吗
Do you think he could come in and speak to the class?
嗯  您看哈
Um... you know...
我认为这不太现实  他现在腿脚不那么利落了
I don't think that's a good idea. He's not moving around very well anymore.
宇航对膝盖很不好
Astronauting is very hard on the knees.
好吧  如果你能请他过来  我会给你额外加分的
Well, if you bring him in, I'll give you extra credit.
然后你的成绩可能会提高到A哦
And it could bring your grade up to an "A".
哈  英语能拿A
Huh. An "A" in English.
哇  夫复何求啊
Woo! Can't ask for more better than that.
下一个
Next!
好啦  对于小公主的角色
Okay. For the role of the young Princess,
有请查莉·邓肯
presenting Charlie Duncan.
你好  查莉
Hi, Charlie.
好啦  查莉  说一遍台词
Okay, Charlie, say the line.
查莉  嘿
Charlie, hey.
查莉  听好啊  你的台词是
Charlie, remember, your line is...
陛下  我为舞蹈而生
"Your majesty, I was born to dance".
好吗  你来说一遍啊
Okay? Now you say it.
我耳朵刚刚关机了
I turned my ears off.
好吧  稍稍等我们一下好吗
Here, just... can you give us a minute?
好的
Okay.
下一位是
Who's next?
您好  我是塔米
Hi, I'm Tammy.
你好  塔米  随时开始就好
Hi, Tammy. Whenever you're ready.
陛下  我为舞蹈而生
Your majesty, I was born to dance.
塔米  刚刚好精彩
Tammy, that was very good.
哇  你意下如何
Wow. What did you think?
我感觉有点太显摆了
A little show-offy for my taste.
拜托  她太好了
Oh, come on! She's fantastic.
谁知道呢  我是说  对  她是能演戏跳舞念台词
Yeah, I don't know. I mean, yeah sure, she can act and dance and say the line,
但除了那些东西  还剩什么了
but once you take that away, then what do you have?
查莉
Charlie.
好的
Okay.
我们有两位杰出的候选人来竞争小公主的角色
We have got two great candidates for the role of the young Princess.
让我们来公正客观地评价他们
Let's just compare them objectively.
查莉  对
Charlie versus...
汉密
Hammy.
是塔米
Tammy.
哦  太晚了  我已经写上“汉密”了
Oh, it's too late. I've already wrote a "Hammy".
好啦  第一项
Okay! First category...
可爱程度  查莉得10分哦
Cuteness. Well, Charlie gets a 10.
没  没问题是吧
No... no question there.
然后  嗯  塔米
And, uh, Tammy...
我们大度一点给她5分吧
Let's be generous and give her a five.
才5分
A five?
太高了吗  那我给她4分
Is that too high? I'll make it a four.
然后  下一项  人格魅力
Okay, next category... personality.
-塔米笑得很甜  -配着死鲨鱼的眼睛
- Tammy has a nice smile. - With dead shark eyes.
我再给出一个4分
I'll make it another four.
查莉得10分
Charlie gets a 10.
那说台词的能力呢
How about the ability to say lines?
哦  是啊  这可能有  嗯
Oh. Yeah. There is some, uh...
一点点小争论
There is some debate there.
这么地  每人给个五分吧
You know what? Let's just give them each a five.
结果出来了  查莉完胜啊
And there you have it! Charlie is the clear-cut winner!
少来了  泰迪
Oh, Teddy! Come on!
数字不说谎呀  又不是我编的
But the numbers don't lie. I didn't just make them up.
就是你编的
Yes, you did!
艾薇  我会让她开口说台词的
Ivy, I will get her to say the line.
我是小查莉密语者
I'm The Charlie Whisperer.
好吧  就让她来演吧
All right. She's got the part.
我都不知道该怎么和塔米解释
I don't know how I'm gonna explain this to Tammy.
甭担心  她以后机会多的是
Don't worry about Tammy. She's gonna get tons of parts.
她太牛了
She's amazing.
- 哎呀  有饼干  - 不是给你吃的
- Ooh, cookies.  - Hey, they're not for you.
- 是给伯特准备的  - 伯特要过来
- They're for Bert.  - Bert's coming over?
是的  你能在这待着不  你比较会跟老年人相处
Yeah, and can you stick around? You have a way with old people.
平时我觉着挺受不了的  不过现在我需要你
Usually, it creeps me out, but now I need you.
嗨  伯特  请进
Hey! Bert! Come on in.
我在街对面都住了二十年了
I've been living across the street from you people for 20 years
你才头一次邀请我来
and I've never been invited over.
我们比较害羞
We're shy.
害羞  我听你妈说你俩整天在家又唱又跳
Shy? I hear that mother of yours singing and dancing all the time!
- 女人嘛  对吧  - 嘿  跟我说说
- Women, huh, Bert?  - Hey, tell me about it.
吃饼干不
Cookie?
好啊
Yeah, sure.
毛衣真不错
That is a nice cardigan.
您穿出了不一样的气质
They don't make them like that anymore.
你说对了
You got that right.
我喜欢你
Now you, I like.
随便你了
Anyhoo, Bert.
我想问问你能不能去我班级
I was wondering if you could come to my class
讲述一下你神奇的职业生涯
and talk about your amazing career.
神奇  我只是个邮递员而已
Amazing? I was a Mailman.
不错  不错
Good stuff. Good stuff.
不过让我们来
But let me just suggest one small...
做一个小小的调整
A little tiny tweak.
不用邮递员  咱换一个词
Instead of Mailman, let's use a different word.
邮差
Letter carrier?
我想到的是宇航员
I was thinking Astronaut.
你想让我撒谎
You want me to lie?
邮递员怎么了
What's wrong with being a Mailman?
没怎  只是现在的孩子吧  想吸引他们注意力比较难
Nothing. It's just that the kids these days, they're not as easily entertained.
他们都喜欢什么电子游戏  小发明还有小器具啥的
What with the video games, the gizmos and the gadgets.
真是堕落的一代啊
We're losing our country, Bert.
我也老是对我的收音机说这句话
That's what I always say when I'm talking to my radio.
这么说  你答应了
So... so you'll do it?
没有  我才不会谎报我的职业
No! I'm not gonna lie about my job.
那你愿意谎报啥呢
What will you lie about?
旅游怎么样  有没有可能让您说去过木星
Your vacations? And could one of them possibly have been to Jupiter?
你缺心眼吧
Are you off your nut?
谁把你养大的啊
Who raised you anyway?
嘿  伯特
Hey, Bert.
好吧  这不是你的错
Okay, it's not your fault.
查莉  只有一句台词而已
Charlie, it's just one line.
跟着我念
Say it with me.
陛下  我为舞蹈而生
"Your majesty, I was born to dance".
快说呀  求你了  查莉
Charlie, come on, please.
姑娘们  进展如何
Hey, girls. What's going on?
查莉就是不愿说台词
I can't get Charlie to say her line.
你不是会用意念让她说的吗
Why don't you just do it with your mind?
如果你不嘲笑我的话  我可以让你帮忙
If you're done mocking me, I could really use your help here.
甜心
Oh, sweetheart.
我不会不嘲笑你的
I'll never be done mocking you.
好吧  放松点  我有办法
Okay, relax. I have an idea.
查莉  我们今天来读一本新的有趣的故事书
Okay, Charlie. We're gonna read a fun new book.
名字就叫  陛下  我为舞蹈而生
It's called "your majesty, I was born to dance".
噢  这名字可真棒  你要说一遍吗
Ohh! That sounds like a great title. You wanna say that?
对  你想和书中的公主一样说这句话不
Yeah, do you wanna say it like the Princess in the book?
那是只狗狗
That's a dog.
是个戴着隐形王冠的狗狗公主
Well, it's a doggy Princess with an invisible tiara.
我想看别的书
I want another book.
别啊  查莉  你会说这句的
Come on, Charlie. You can say the line.
陛下  我为舞蹈而生
"Your majesty, I was born to dance".
哈哈  现在看看谁才是小查莉密语者
Oh! Who's The Charlie Whisperer now?
下面有请  伯特·窦艮  著名宇航员
All right, here he is... Bert Doogan, famous Astronaut.
伯特
Well, Bert.
非常感谢你能来
Thank you so much for joining us.
介绍一下你自己吧
Why don't you tell us a little bit about yourself?
能让他拿掉头盔吗
Could Bert take off his helmet?
不行  下一个问题
Uh, no. Next question.
这么说我们的演讲者其实说话都不清楚
So we have a speaker who can't actually speak?
好了孩子们  大家排好队过来摸摸伯特的头盔
Okay, kids. Let's all line up and we can all touch Bert's helmet,
然后他就得走了
and then he'll be on his way.
我先来
I'll go first.
盖比  他是谁
Gabe, who is this?
伯特啊  我邻居
It's Bert, my neighbor.
他还真是年轻的不可思议呢
Bert looks surprisingly young.
谢谢你亲爱的  你这么说真是太好了
Oh, thank you, dear. That's sweet of you to say.
盖比  我要听实话
Gabe, I want the truth.
好吧  实话就是
Okay. The truth is that...
在伯特最后一次任务期间  他穿过一个蛀洞  然后就穿越了
On his last mission, Bert went through a wormhole sending him back in time.
盖比·邓肯  我早该想到的
Gabe Duncan, I should have known better.
- 可不是么  早该如此  - 我该走了
- You know, you really should have. - Well, I should get going.
飞向无限
To infinity and beyond!
亲爱的
Oh hey, hon'.
我的宝贝儿子在这呢
Hey! There's my baby boy.
鲍伯  亲爱的  你
Um, Bob, hon', you...
- 你是不是忘了啥  - 这个吗
- You missing something? - Wha... oh! This?
我决定更新一下我的工作思路
Aw, I just decided to update the work threads.
亲爱的  那啥
Well, sweetie.
你是除虫师啊  你制服的首要功能
You're an exterminator. Isn't the point of your uniform
不是应该保护你不被叮咬吗
to protect you from things that sting and bite?
嘿  我的二头肌会保护我的
Hey, these cannons are my protection.
哦
Oh.
爸爸疯了
Daddy's gone crazy.
妈妈会治好他的
Mama's gonna fix it.
- 嘿  - 你去哪了
- Hey. - Where have you been?
- 查莉呢  - 她在家
- And where's Charlie? - She's at home.
- 啥  - 她不愿来
- What?! - She refused to come.
我很友善得请她来
And then when I asked her nicely,
结果她捂住耳朵就跑开了
she turned off her ears and she ran away from me.
你怎么能这么对我
How could you do this to me?
不能全怪我好吧
Look, it's not completely my fault.
你要是合格的导演当初就应该选塔米
Okay? A good Director would have chosen Tammy!
泰迪
Teddy, the...
小公主两分钟后就要上台  我们该怎么办
The young Princess goes on in two minutes. What are we gonna do?
交给我了
I'll take care of it.
陛下  我为舞蹈而生
Your majesty, I was born to dance!
嘿  这是啥情况
Hey. What's going on?
弗恩  你在这干嘛
Vern, what are you doing here?
兄弟  我在这是因为我爱你
I'm here because I love you, man.
不妙
Uh-oh.
鲍伯  亲爱的  过来  坐我旁边
Bob, honey. Come here. Have a seat next to me.
亲爱的  我们大家有些话要说
Now, sweetie, we have some things we'd like to say,
所以请你好好听着
so please just hear us out.
泰迪  你先说
Teddy? You start.
老爸  我怀念以前的你
Dad, I miss the old you.
就是说  那个穿衣服不会比我更紧身的普通人
You know, the normal guy whose clothes aren't tighter than mine.
PJ  到你了
Okay. P.J.
老爸
Dad...
我希望咱俩买衣服能去不同的店
I want us to shop at different stores.
我不想和你穿一样的裤子
I don't want us to have the same pants.
必须郑重声明  我喜欢你的新形象
For the record, I love your new look!
简直是搞笑的金矿啊
It's a comedic gold mine.
- 比如说  - 好了好了  谢谢你  盖比
- For instance... - Uh, uh, thank you, Gabe.
弗恩
Vern?
你有什么想说的呢
Would you like to share?
看看我  老大
Look at me, boss.
你就为了显摆功夫  害得我把血肉之躯暴露给敌人
I had to expose my flesh to the enemy just so you could show off your guns.
老鲍  你这是怎么了
What's going on, Bob?
你是正处于中年危机什么的吗
Are you having some sort of a mid-life crisis?
不是
No!
我
I...
好吧我说
All right.
几个月前  我带着托比在公园
A couple of months ago I'm in the park with Toby and, uh...
有人以为我是他爷爷
Somebody thought I was his grandfather.
就因为某个陌生人的不靠谱言论
So you went through all of this
你就这么折腾自己
because of some off-handed comment from a stranger?
没错
Yeah!
但是这激励了我减肥  保持体型呀
But it... guys, it inspired me to lose weight, get in shape.
你的新体型很好
And your new body is great.
但是你用来打扮它的衣服
What you've chosen to put on your new body...
就不那么好了
Not so great.
老爸
Dad.
需要我们帮忙把你今天买的衣服退回去吗
Will you accept our help and return those clothes today?
外面有辆车正等着带你去和你年龄相符的服装店
There's a car waiting outside to take you to an age-appropriate store.
好吧  行  我去
All right, fine. I'll go.
不过你们得等二十分钟
But, um... you're gonna have to give me
我把这裤子给脱下来
20 minutes to get out of these pants.
小查莉
Well, Charlie.
老爸换回了以前的衣服  所以家里又少了一位未成年人
Dad returned all the clothes, so there's one less teenager in the house.
其它方面
And in other news...
喂  不要吵
Hey! Keep it down in there!
盖比在学校惹麻烦了
Gabe got in trouble at school,
所以现在他正和我们邻居伯特进行一次真正的采访
so now he has to interview our neighbor Bert for real.
我说到哪了
Now where was I?
1983年
1983.
最贵的邮票卖二十美分
The first-class stamp cost 20 cents.
而且四位数的邮编出现了
And the zip plus-four code was established.
现在邮编是四位了
Now the Z.P.4. Code,
原本的邮编只有三位哦
was originally supposed to be just a Z.P.3.
这儿有点复杂了  要跟上我的思路
Now this is where it gets complicated, so just stay with me.
看来盖比得在那待一段时间了
It looks like Gabe's gonna be there a while.
祝他好运吧  小查莉
Wish him good luck, Charlie.
弗恩  我来教你塑造体形
All right, Vern. You wanna look good
以便穿上那身制服更好看些
in that uniform, we gotta get you into shape.
好了
All right.
开始之前  我们来拉伸一下肌肉
Now before we begin, we need to stretch out.
你还真灵活
You are limber!
好了  我们来做几个仰卧起坐
All right, let's try some sit-ups.
注意看我的技巧
Now watch my technique.
好  到你了
All right, your turn.
你还好不  弗恩
Vern? You okay?
老大  我想我是一次做得太快太多了
I think I did a little bit too much too fast, boss.